Onaje Oladuwa

• Atlanta, GA

✓ onaje.oladuwa@gmail.com

(404) 263-5103 **in** ooladuwa

📢 ooladuwa 🍠 ooladuwa

Profile

Full-stack software engineering student with a background in education. Focused on providing meaningful, genuine contributions to colleagues, stakeholders, and end-users. Experienced and visionary educator with demonstrated history of working with diverse populations, building community, and implementing restorative practices/social-emotional learning. Served as a teacher, department chair, grade-level chair, and coach.

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub

Projects

Project One

One sentence to describe what app does or what type of tool it is, don't repeat title of project in this description sentence.

Project Two

One sentence to describe what app does or what type of tool it is, don't repeat title of project in this description sentence.

Education

Lambda School

2020 - present

Tufts University, B.A. English & Sociology 1997

Le Prieure

1995 | France
French Language and International
Relations

Professional Experience

Teacher/Grade Level Chair, KIPP Metro Atlanta 06/2012 – 06/2017 | Atlanta, GA

- Developed and installed Earth Science curriculum
- Outperformed network, district and state in 6th Grade Georgia Milestones by 6% average
- Supervised, coached, and evaluated grade-level teachers; provided detailed feedback and hands-on metrics for improvement
- Delivered professional development sessions around building classroom community, increasing literacy in science, restorative practices, and community circles
- Automated discipline and parent-contact systems to significantly return more than 1 hour of productivity to teacher days

Lead English Teacher, *Hoban Eton Language Academy* 08/2008 – 01/2012 | Cheonan, South Korea

- Designed and implemented structured language curriculum focused on developing English proficiency within a three-year program
- Provided ongoing/detailed capability evaluations for all students on a weekly/monthly basis
- Observed and coached Korean teachers

Teacher/Grade Level Chair/Football Coach,

KIPP South Fulton Academy

06/2004 - 12/2006 | Atlanta, GA

- Planned rigorous curriculum; Achieved 96% content mastery on state assessments; 20% growth on the ITBS
- Led out-of-state trips to North Carolina and NYC
- Created football program; Head coach

Teacher, HOPE Academy

08/2003 - 05/2004 | Cleveland, OH

- Utilized innovative techniques to achieve 16% gain in science content mastery as measured by end-of-grade assessments
- Conceived and implemented a schedule which increased student opportunities to explore creative outlets

Teacher/Assistant Coach,

Teach For America/Central High School 08/2000 - 05/2002 | Helena, AR

- Selected as *one of* 1,200 *of* 11,000 applicants to serve in a national service corps of recent college graduates
- Designed test preparation curriculum for students which raised ACT scores an average of 6 points
- Identified from over 3,000 active corps members to participate in TFA Video Initiative as a model teacher

Organisations

Teach For America

Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, Inc.